it is something that neither no single
one of us could could do right so the
idea isn't to bring your already made
ideas into it and then say this is the
way we do it it still allows something
new to emerge from the conversation
itself including who you are what you
bring to it so if anybody would like to
start and share what you think is
currently happening in the social media
play space what you like and what you
don't like and I'm always willing to
start
no nonsense about just please go all
right
virtual media I didn't make notes
because this is like it's a little bit
like fish and water like this is where I
think a lot of the power lies and yet it
didn't even occur to me with the social
but the media right to break it off and
it was like entertainment and
information allow you up in one second
Eric and it was it's but social media is
that it's where we get our information
now and it's where we get our
entertainment and it's where people are
and so any social media has to have that
people by definition it has to have a
certain number of people that you can
interact with it you know and don't know
and at the same time it needs to be
information and that we get information
it's trustworthy and that's definitely
not happening and we don't trust
Facebook or Twitter to be the ones to
put those things into place so we need
like third parties to create things and
how do we trust those third parties we
have people there's the informations
become echo chambers the entertainment
has become addiction as opposed to do I
enjoy this right as an individual am i
enjoying being here or is it causing me
stress and anxiety is it taking away
from my life or is it adding into my
life and then of course it's a society
exponentially what does that look like
and information same it's like I can go
down my own a curb chambers and have
things proven to me but what I want is
to have one place to go it's like
actually understand and see the black
and white as well as the grey and that I
will I will stop sharing I just muted if
anyone wants to go to raise their hand
and we can unmute just because it's hard
with the background noise and then I'll
open it up for discussion at the end who
would like to go next welcome Eric
all right oh I was actually just waiting
hello but I'm happy to go next that's
fine that's fine too
[Laughter]
yeah so I guess for me the problem with
social media as it currently stands is
that it's a commercial operation and I
mean a lot of you just mentioned a lot
of the problems that that brings with it
and the echo chamber thing but work for
me the worst thing is that it's in a
social media platforms interest to get
people pissed off at each other right
because then they get into heated
arguments and they stay on the site for
ages and ages and ages you know and so
there is there is actually incentive to
create agitation among people so yeah
the things which are incentivized under
a commercial model are gonna be
profoundly destructive to society I mean
there's an Indian guy a comment what his
name is he used to be one of the senior
engineers at Facebook he helped design
the earlier versions of the algorithm
and he's been going around doing talks
about how it was designed to create a
dopamine fueled social validation
feedback loop system right where people
go on social media in order to get likes
in order to get views in order to get
comments and that every time they get
one of these things they get a little
kick of dopamine in their in the brain
reward system and this is profound you
know really really really addictive
stuff and it's in our biology no there's
no escaping from this and so it seems to
me that I mean I know Jubilee you want
to rebuild new social media platforms
from the ground up and there should
absolutely be going on and there are
various people I know who are involved
in trying to put these kinds of things
together but I would also like to and
I'm not saying don't do that what I'm
saying is in addition to there I think
it will be worth focusing on the notion
of trying to repurpose the ones that we
already have right because they already
have huge user bases and so if somehow
or another what Jordan was talking about
in his medium post if somehow or another
a fiduciary relationship could be
created between social media platforms
and their users such that the enormous
amount of information that they gather
about you is to be used only in your
best interests right it is only there to
serve you not to serve their advertising
revenues and so on and and if that
change could be made and I'm not saying
it's easy but if that change could be
made I mean that that revolutionizes the
whole nature of social media platforms
overnight and then censorship is another
issue but i reaiiy - that I've already
talked actually I haven't had my five
minutes so it
about censorship as well there's an idea
Eric good solution reason we don't have
five minutes for each of the times just
oh right so you're welcome to continue
if you want no no no I did the
censorship is just another issue and
I'll stop there I'll just I'll leave it
at that yeah go ahead well great thanks
the guy that you mentioned was shamatha
poly pitaya who was VP of growth at
Facebook so he was actually the guy who
led the team that led the growth efforts
from 30 to 800 million users at Facebook
which is I mean it can be interpreted as
greater sheet achievement but then I
think when we talk about what is the
problem of social media I think we
should start with what does it actually
mean to have social media and to have
just the possibility of social media and
what does it mean for us to be able to
design the social words for billions of
people right and that's where suddenly
the design question is actually a really
profound and really deep philosophical
question of if we have this fiduciary
responsibility and if we if we don't
just ourselves and the word and
say yeah we we just designed stuff and
people obviously use it and so they
obviously like it so if we actually
embrace our fiduciary responsibility and
ask what's actually in the best interest
of the people using this and at this
scale what's actually in the best
interest of not just these people but
society at large basically all sentient
beings on planet earth what's in the
best interest of like what's the highest
thing we could even serve and then we
see okay that's evolution and that life
and evolution obviously want us to do
our best to not go extinct and to be
stewards of the power that we that we
gained with exponential technology and
once we once you say okay we we actually
take our fiduciary responsibilities
seriously and we that is what we want to
serve because this is what the best
cognitive science the best kind of all
philosophical
situations that you can make adamantly
converge on this that you want to
empower people to make better choices
that are SS only consider it as possible
and so if you want to do this how the
fact that we do this and how the do
we do this
in a landscape that is the attention
economy with the race to the bottom of
the brainstem where everyone is
basically based on their business model
and based on the hundreds of billions of
dollars stacked on that business model
incentivized to extract as much
attention as possible so yeah that's a
really weight problem okay um definitely
hard to talk about this in a short
period of time I would say that yeah the
incentives are off we only have
essentially social media platforms that
are not they're not built in the best
interest of the users that's like
probably the overall thesis statement
how that get Matt gets manifested is in
you know 18 different ways that get more
specific but that's the overall it does
get manifested in making it addictive
gets manifested in from my perspective
mostly the design stuff there's so much
thing there's so many things they could
do they could add a button that says
like say you're talking to someone
through comments they could have a
button that says let's create a meeting
like they could do that but they don't
like there are so if you're a programmer
there's the possibilities are endless
what you could do with these
interactions but they are not in the
incent the incentive is to keep the
users on it as long as possible it's
always going to mess up what's good for
you obviously it is a tool with great
potential for connecting people the way
see it is it doesn't connect me to the
people I care about the most what I
observe is that people are moving to
text messages group text they're moving
to group telegram what's that most
people I know have moved to group text
messaging or group messaging things
because social media is a dumpster fire
and it's just not working for connecting
them and it's like kind of going back in
time it's like there's so much more we
could do but group text isn't going to
work the way that it's kind of like
we've got this awesome tool called the
internet and we're just we're using it
at like 40% capacity to what how it
could really connect you to the people
that you love and your neighbors and all
of that do it and then I guess I lastly
I'd say well so you have the money and
this incentive structures are off you
also have the entertainment problem I
think we're mixing too many things I
love news I love entertainment and I
want to be connected with my friends and
family are those supposed to all be done
in the same place like I I don't think
so that's why I'm more of a fan of like
let's create something new that does
this specific thing LinkedIn used to be
a networking for for business
guess what you can share cat videos on
LinkedIn now and I've seen it like if I
was running LinkedIn I would be like
this cute you know let's keep that
entertainment type of stuff somewhere
else because we're trying to be this
professional space over here but we're
trying to do too many things now you
have Facebook marketplace so like it's
trying to do too many things from my
perspective with one platform I guess
that's my rant on the problems thank you
also have a couple
we can kind of open it up for open
discussion I like what Daniel had to say
about the best interest of the user that
brought up for me is like who decides
and what the best interest of users like
right now Twitter LinkedIn Facebook all
of them are there for profit which is
not a great incentive for seeing what
that looks like in the world but it's a
common incentive whereas my idea of
what's best interest for the user versus
well versus Daniel's versus Eric's is
going to be very different we can argue
about what's most profitable if we're
caring about game a but in game B what's
the best interest with it and that's
when are the questions that I'd ask the
game be spaces like are you designing it
for you or are you designing it for them
if I need everyone else to start
behaving and they need to act better and
they need to be less entertained and
less attractive dopamine versus I want a
place I can go to for information a
connection and I want to be in control
of my own data and I want other people
to have a say in that so that we can
build something that does have the
people and the spaces that was just what
what is in the best interest of the user
is what I think I know right but that
doesn't extrapolate necessarily I think
that's what this thing breaks down that
everyone starts their own with this idea
of the best interest of the user without
really looking at how can we create this
from so that it made meets our
individual needs collectively the Union
I think you need a way to experiment
because you know it's just like in
programming they run like different
models a b c and d on a website you
actually have like four different
versions and it randomizes what you land
on and then they do statistical analysis
to find out did they make more purchases
did more people get to the website and
make a purchase and like they look at
all that well I just think that we don't
have the we don't I don't have the
funding I don't have the people power
I'm not a programmer myself to do the
experiments and like I still think there
won't be one platform for all these
thing
I I have you know 40 different apps on
my phone and I think that that's okay to
have different platforms for different
things I think like I have friends that
love tick tock I'm not trying to compete
with tick tock I think tick tock is
doing what it is doing like really well
but it's not doing other things really
well so I wouldn't want to like try to
add scientific articles or something to
tick tock like now you're mixing
different things that I don't think you
need to try to do alright so we are at
the 15-minute mark so now it can very
easily go into you can still bring your
stuff up so how did we do it constantly
the next piece is what does your version
of social media look like it doesn't
need to match it's like in your perfect
version of the Future 5 10 100 years the
future however long you need it to be
what does that look like to you can I
just because I think it makes a nice
introduction from from the problems that
we have so first off I think abt testing
is it's really effective at what it does
but there's this nice if you take a be
limit to a be testing to its to its max
every website basically ends up being a
porn site because they're like inherent
in that kind of measurement is is just
test like maximizing for engagement with
which leads you down can Paleolithic
biology and then the other thing is
what's in our best interest it's like
that's a question of values and that's
like there are some things like if these
things are good at universally you
globally creating a mental health
condemning right then there must be some
things about them that actually
University problematic and I believe
that we can turn these around and can
look at okay what is it that is
universally beneficial and in our best
interest
so just like and and just saying we
don't want suffering and we do it we
don't want addiction for example it's a
pretty good selling point because then
we can say okay if we don't want
addiction intentionality is a pretty
good antidote to that and so whatever it
is that we want we want the kind of
intentionality to to balance that out
and then I think the third point is that
ultimately the question of values and
the question of what's our best interest
is not at this point not only about kind
of opinions and what some people feel
good about and don't think I think
ultimately in a way it is there's a hard
limit and that happening with this do we
manage to change our collective behavior
to the point that we end up being a
viable civilization in this efficient
timeline I'm just gonna invite you just
transform into what you want with a
beautiful future you want to create so I
like what we're not creating what do you
want it to look like for you or for
society it doesn't matter but like what
do you want it to look like yes and so
what I would based on that what I would
love to see is us coming together around
values that like us finding finding ways
of the green on a set of venues that we
agree on our best interest and finding
ways to make these values and agreement
with these values as accessible as
possible because it's easy for us to
value mindfulness if we sit well fed in
warm houses with good internet
connection and the laptop it's very hard
to care about mindfulness when we are
hungry don't really have a house and
striving to get to get water and so
making kind of agreeing on values that
are good for us all and making that
possible and just building technology
that helps us become capable of meeting
the supplement of actually deepening our
like opening our eyes and seeing what's
going on in the world and deepening our
care for that
increasing our identity increasing the
circles of belonging that we feel
connected to making us become citizens
of the world and and seeing ourselves as
that and then helping us make sense of
okay based on all these things going on
in the world what is it that I can do
what is it that like what's what's mine
to contribute here and how can
technology and how are we to to live up
to my venues and to really be
intentional about how I use my time how
I use my intention and what I do
why becoming what I contribute you so
thank you well and you also want to
share what they're beautiful version of
social media looks like in the future
I'd actually like to pick up on a couple
of things here because they all feed
into into kind of what I would like to
see it become so this notion of agreeing
on values I think is I think is a
mistake as soon as you want everyone to
agree on the same I know we don't know I
am aware I'm getting there I'm getting
there and so what I would like to see
rather than agreeing on a particular set
of values is just agreeing in good faith
and in earnest that we are going to
endeavour to make this about the user
experience right and and not that you
know what is what is in the best
interest of the user that's the value
right what those interests interests are
is a constant state of debate and
argument and development right but that
that thing that notion of what we are
doing is in the best interest of either
that is held primary right and that is
earnestly followed in the same way that
as you were saying before DubLi you can
argue about what is the most profitable
model but we all agree that making a
profit is the most important thing in
game a right so in the same way you know
argue about what is the what is in the
best interest of the user but the point
of being in the best interest of the
user that is something on which we all
agree right and the other thing I wanted
to pick up on which also feeds in terms
that Daniel was saying about different
platforms for different things that
Facebook is trying to do too many things
and it doesn't do any of them very well
kind of thing and and I agree with that
however my vision is of a
single platform into which everyone is
connected and into which and within
which everyone can tailor their own
platform within a platform if you sue I
mean right so they can create exactly
what they want within the grand
framework of this whole thing in which
everybody is connected right and within
that they can choose how they want to
connect to other people what their menu
looks like blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah that's it that's my thing
thank you Eric and you did it
beautifully I'm sorry for interrupting
who would like to go next
I can go next I I'm still in the process
of basically looking for angels of angel
investors I've sent pitch decks to them
I've run this by give us your angel
investor speech what is that platform
you want it to be saying that I can't
say everything because I'm trying to do
a specific type of idea I've I've run
this by two different tech development
firms and they quoted me about 30,000 to
40,000 US dollars is what they could
build it for so in terms of what would
be in the best interest of the user I
want an extreme amount of like news feed
control I wouldn't really call it a news
feed so the person has control over what
they see on their main screen what this
looks like is like even if you open up
Instagram snapchat Facebook all these
things it's like playing the lottery you
don't really know what you're gonna see
and in what order so you scroll through
and you occasionally you hit a something
that you do
see and most of the time that's
associated with a person that posted
something we kind of got to scroll
through three or four different things
you didn't really want to see - you hit
oh great I saw mom posted this thing but
I have no idea why I saw whatever the
heck I saw and what order so I want to
be able to put in order on purpose what
I see in what order so that's the first
thing the second thing is a huge
emphasis on controlling who sees what so
I have different groups of friends I
have work buddies I have my music
friends I have my festival friends I
have my church buddies I have family I
have my friends from out of state I have
my local friends these are all different
groups what I want is or what I would
envision is a way so when I am posting
something then it prompts me to select
which what is the visibility of this
post am I do I want this to be seen by
everyone or basically I have like
checkboxes I want this to be
I'm gonna check off family and local for
this one and then I'm gonna do another
post and I'm gonna check off these are
for my just my art and festival friends
now some most platforms don't have
anything like this
Facebook technically does but it's so
buried down in the settings they're
making it difficult to do this on
purpose from what I can tell so high a
couple minutes left but I want Bentley
and me to be able to say what our
visions are is there anything else you
want to add to what your vision my
emphasis on who's seeing my things
literally built into how I post thank
you
Bentley I know you've got some thoughts
what would you what would your vision
look like yeah it sounds quite a bit
like what Eric and Daniel have said as
far as being able to control what you
see I think it'd be great to have a
marketplace of
different algorithms on what you see and
you can build your own or you can use
other people some of it AI some of it
not would be really interesting and I
really as far as me I don't even know if
I'd call it a social media platform
because I figure all my data I need that
level of control so if someone sends me
an email or a text I'd like to see it in
that feet so that's kind of something
I've talked about in the past the being
able to share that you know control who
kind of sees it that's that's a good
idea
I have used the Facebook groups to do
that it is very challenging
we're not groups but there's there's a
way to do it in Facebook but it's
challenging yeah so I don't even know if
I'd call it a social media platform I
think we need to kind of disentangle all
this and have it or we can we can choose
all the information coming in and kind
of how it goes out and not be connected
to I mean I would want that front end to
be for all my social media presences
regardless of the platform yeah that's
what I've been thinking all right I'll
try to share mine quickly so um a lot of
what has been shared already I would
like to have unlike what Daniel said I
actually do really care that there's 40
different apps on my phone and the phone
real estate I want one app which is my
front end that I have the dashboard to
see what's going on I want one pool of
people and data that we can use and I
want to complete control over my own
data at my own connections I want to be
able to have a dashboard for my social
media whatever we're calling it that
helps me live my life better eat better
under my conditions live healthier under
my conditions have real connections in
the real world and online under my
conditions my schedule my interests and
to be able to orchestrate that to be
able to say what isn't isn't working for
me in the user experience and to be able
to help make it better if it's not
working to be able to truly diversify
what I need from it without that taking
away from what
and other unique user needs to use how
can we have those trade-offs with of
them actually being trade-offs and
having one one piece of real estate on
my phone that connects to all of that
information and then if I wanted to
split it up great if I wanted my food
app and my financial app but if I have
one place I can see it as a dashboard
and I know I can trust it and all of
that stuff feeds into it that's what I
want to my social media platform if
anyone else has some closing thoughts
for this that someone else brought up
and I most transfer over into the my
favorite part it occurred to me well
Bentley was talking that the notion of
the distinction between emails IMS texts
messages blah blah blah that's all going
to disappear really quickly right and
there's just going to be messages and
and so that I think yeah that's all I
just just
I'm just curious Judy kind of this
sounds a lot like I mean Kevin had me
live my life better that's sounds almost
like it so from proofing it right
where's the social aspect well that
would be me living my life better I
don't want to live my life better in
isolation so for me to eat my life if
for me to eat better I would need to be
connected to other people who we can
share recipes ensure that in order to be
able to you know I mean to have a book
club I need other people there and I'll
be able to have this conversation I
needed for other of you to be here so
there's always a social aspect brought
into it of like all the people with my
same medical conditions you know what I
mean share in data and and information
to be able to put that back together
and that was my answer does that answer
that well Daniels got his hand transfer
over yeah just the idea that whatever
this my personal perspective on this
whatever this is is going to connect me
to the people I need to be connected to
that I want to be connected to way
faster I'm gonna get to the information
where's the barbecue tomorrow night
what's going on Sunday are we going to
see that movie or not I want I'm going
to get to that meaningful information
way faster so I'm on my platform way
less in in you know a way less amount of
the time I'm gonna get to what I want to
see right away so I can put my phone
down and get on to living that's like my
vision alright so we're at the half an
hour mark so we can transfer on to the
major portion which is what could we
actually create right now with 10,000
people and $100,000 so yeah what could
we create with 10,000 people and
$100,000
I think starting with kind of I don't
know what it when you say create how far
you want to get maybe I mean so we could
kind of kind of think what are our
shared values like we talked about in a
social media platform which it could be
simply like we just discussed what is
that to make what's best for the end for
the individual user and stuff like that
and then start working on some
requirements I don't know how far you
get with that and all with that money in
that time yeah I mean I would I'd think
it'd be nice to create a a central kind
of hub and just start with either email
or Facebook or something like that and
then add on different features and
options as we need so I guess the core
thing would be making something that
reads the existing social media
platforms or email and stuff and then a
viewer and not even include editing or
data entry and you could probably do
that for that level of resource
so sorry Bentley just just just so I'm
clear on what he said you're talking
about an app which is none of the social
media platforms but which can tap into
them and you can select which pages or
whatever of which platforms you want it
to display so you is that basically what
you're suggesting yeah that's my side
there's legal but it's a start right I
mean it's not there's not the thing but
it's a but it's a start it's a step in
that direction yeah just that slimming
down all the that you don't want
and and yeah yeah and in that case I
don't really 10,000 people to be on it
even if you created that happened yeah
that's right for you and so that would
you know I mean it's not the Facebook I
would like to have 10,000 people and
figure out what are our common let's say
we did get 10,000 people together we
found our common top three common values
created a social media platform just for
those 10,000 people so that we could
interact and coordinate so it's clearly
not to keep in touch with your high
school friends and your extended family
it's how can this 10,000 people create
something that we that we have a big
enough threshold with just us that we
want to use it and what does that look
like and then if those 10,000 guaranteed
some of them aren't going to be aligned
with those values and they're gonna fall
away so then we need to find new people
with those values to record if we
started from the value system but
starting from zooming out to the
elephant what do we get on a social
media platform and how can we get the
good without without the bad well we
first would have to agree on the good
and the bad or find ways to to negate
the trade-offs which maybe isn't
feasible that's not I think one point
where this where there could be huge
leverage and which also connects to
repurposing the existing platforms is
just connecting what is everything that
we think sucks about social media and
then kind of cataloging that in
connection to what are the ways in which
we are being manipulated here and
creating something like a behave like
creating something like an behavior
design settings page so imagine in
facebook you could really design your
own interface you could select that you
want to see stopping cues instead of an
infinite feat let's say you could
kind of badge notifications together
let's say he could group friends and
family stuff and kind of educational
dated stuff so that you have different
feeds for the things that you care about
and so really kind of showing an example
showing by design how it could be better
and how once you give people control you
can also give them control over the
stuff that was currently hijacking them
and how you could turn that off and once
that is established and once once people
see that that is possible I think that
could really lead to a shift in how we
think about it and to more pressure on
these companies so we can't really see
Congress out legislating advertisements
the business model because there's just
too much interest stacked on that but we
could imagine something like a behavior
design setting page where people could
really just see all the design
techniques that I use to measure to
manipulate them and the setting to turn
them off and that could be mandatory for
all social like for all media platforms
above a certain threshold or whatever
and I think that would get us a long way
I I don't understand how you're
proposing we turn these things off I
mean I get that we can make a list of
all the things we think that are
manipulating us I mean those lists I'm
not even sure we have to make it just
google it like from my personal
perspective at this point we're pretty
aware of of the problems I think that
when it comes to advertising that is
part of how you advertise to get people
to switch to something that's better for
them it's just like advertising you know
other things you try to say here's the
problem with what you're using and
here's the solution I kind of back off
from wanting to advertise problems
without having the solution ready to go
otherwise that's just annoying to people
there's something about this 10,000
people hundred thousand dollar model
which gets rights because this
advertising thing the problem is that
we've come to expect to be free on
the internet right we don't want to pay
five bucks a month to access Facebook
right we want it to be free and so the
price we pay for that is the
manipulation the selling of our data the
marketizing of our attention and so on
and so you know 10,000 people each
willing to pay $10 a month say or $10 a
quarter or whatever into maintaining
that do not I mean and and so then the
pressure for marketing the pressure for
advertising the pressure for
manipulating you to be on site is
largely removed because the revenue is
there do you not I mean the revenue is
provided by the users as it should be
really in a marketer in a world where
revenue is required really the
appropriate model is for the users to
provide the revenue not indirectly
through the sale of their attention but
directly because they value the service
that the platform provides right sure
what I meant by driving was how do you
advertise your alternatives
that's what I meant by advertising so
you
scribe the problem people have and then
you say and here's the solution to just
describe the problem over and over and
not offer people the solution is tough I
mean my experience in this so far is
that ten thousand dollars could get
something built a alternative platform
no problem I think if I had ten thousand
people to survey like I would find other
people probably in that mix someone who
has experience with advertising someone
who has experience with which I don't
know probably like a need a lawyer in
there and a couple other people that
want to work towards this are the ten
thousand people there to serve our goal
right like we come up with a goal in
they're there to serve and there's there
to be to be surveyed or are we creating
it with and for them right is it
something where well this is my vision
and and they need to cater to my vision
or is it a vision we are creating
together and I don't think one's right
and one is wrong but one has been tried
umpteen times and it's really hard to
take it like part of the reason I'm
getting 10,000 people together is we
don't need to market it if we created a
tent a social media platform
it's truly with and for those 10,000
people they are the market in right
they're like hey there's this thing
that's existing humm be part of it come
be if experience is good enough if it's
enjoyable enough to be on there then
they themselves are the marketing
department but that's not necessary
and so starting something that's maybe
not as game B is gave me like it's not
about how do we fix the world how do we
what would help someone's individual
life get better eat better connect more
with people in real life right if you
want people to connect in real life
instead of online when there's not
academic what does that look like it
looks like me being able to do the
activities that I want right if I want
to play a sport how do I get how do I
get on a team how do I so having a
social media platform actually Mia
caters to that maybe starts with hey how
do you
actually on a personal assistant who is
gonna find all of the cool things out
there for you to do in life and there
was incentive social media platform
maybe ten thousand people are in
Vancouver because it's physically like
one make sense I'm ten thousand people
around the globe knowing what's going on
in the world right sorry but there's a
party there's a barbecue there's this
happening right there's this new
Babbington lead but if instead it was
like I know here's my bucket list here's
what I want to do and actually helped me
work with other people to to fulfill
that so like a Pinterest that we help
each other create our goals right help
each other connect and do that could be
something that would be powerful for
those 10,000 people and then they'd have
more energy and space and time to do
whatever their world-changing saving
life-improving ideas are like just
starting from any part of life and then
focus you know what would help 10,000
people eat better than then they'd have
more energy to but some some common goal
they want to tackle yeah I mean it the
some of the things you're mentioning I
am Not sure have to do with social media
if I want to find a soccer team to join
I could probably google it and find it
I'm not seeing that as something that I
can't do because social media isn't
working well for me I wanna I've tried
to identify what are the ways that
social media itself is not working for
me because some things I do see people
post things on social media that it's
like I mean you google that wouldn't you
like how do I you know help I don't know
how to fix my garbage disposal it's like
maybe they for some reason really want a
friend to show them but like I mean
plenty of people would like Google how
to do that and like I need some healthy
eating plans like is that what we're is
that what social media is for is like
that you know what the internet is for
that is like tackling a smaller problem
instead of a bigger one right you can
find a soccer game a soccer team but can
you coordinate that with everything else
in your life I want to take up a sport I
want to take up in music I want to have
a book club here's everything I want to
have and it finds your timetable finds
other people who also do that and makes
it for you right like if it doesn't help
your life you're not going to use it and
so instead of trying to recreate all of
social media we could recreate on social
media for 10,000 people and it could
work but picking a piece of it it could
really help impact people's lives like
there is this woman called Barbara shear
who has a TED talk where she talks about
people and she just died a week ago and
where she talks about a wish in an
obstacle
everyone has wishes and they have an
obstacle and she has people together in
a room and you give the wish and you
give the obstacle and someone in the
room has a solution for your obstacle
having a social media platform like that
or you're like hey I want to I want to
start an animal rescue group and then
other people just got like are like
what's your obstacle I don't have money
okay here's the funding it doesn't mean
you get the fun you no one's gonna hand
that to you but if there's actually a
platform that was designed for just wish
obstacle right just that is that enough
for people to come on board well if
you've had 10,000 people and asked them
what are your wishes what are your
obstacles how do we design that for you
yeah and it wouldn't be barred or she or
needing to create it and then selling it
to everyone else and she'd have a much
bigger chance she has audience like how
like a piece of it not something to be
the thing it's just like what are little
things like that that might work or the
big bow junctions I feel like what are
your speaking to something like we we
have this gap between our actions and
our intentions and we like if I think
about my best friend like he could have
it better he could have a good day but I
know that at the end of the day he did
for example he meditated in the morning
and he practiced piano and he stretched
it like these are the things that really
matter to him as I know then I then I
care about him doing that and I care
about the people around me taking good
care of themselves
because that and I feel like there's
something about this intention action
gap that we just all share and where I
feel like there's there's potentially a
lot of power in social media to help us
overcome that
is that good attitude that looks like in
particular like with your friends what
would that look like I'm searching again
well let's let's say you say if you like
whatever it is if you want to eat better
if you want to eat better like what how
can we make that easier right like how
can I personally change my behavior such
that I eat more of the stuff that I
actually want to eat not doing that and
so we could and Joe Edelman will use for
the talks about that in terms of venues
and like the things we west goals are
this kind of achievement problem values
are practice problems and so if I have
the value of kind of fresh and healthy
and kind of local food then that's a
practice problem because that has the
problem of where do I get that food how
do I make it such that it's enjoyable
and so on and so if we both share these
values and if we share these practice
problems we can try to figure out how to
practice them together and how to
support each other and doing that and
yeah I feel like that's that's what
social media could be even though it
would be far we may potentially probably
move from I guess my response to like
say doing the local food thing or going
back to the soccer example the way that
I see it is that because I don't have a
good amount of control over who is
seeing what I'm posting on something
like Facebook or Instagram or snapchat
what would help like I could post hey
who wants to do wants to do a soccer
team this spring cool but guess what
it's basically going to my whole
newsfeed and I've got my local friends
I've got my my tech geek friends that
aren't athletes anyways they might
like a group I've got my friends that
live across the country some people in
across the world my point is that if I
post that I'm actually cluttering up
their own information stream by seeing
something that isn't relative to them so
if I had a way to clump my friends and
geographically I had a local friends
group because that information about the
local soccer team or farmers market
thing or whatever is not relevant to
them so I would want to check that box
only my clothes only my geographic close
friends should see this and now we're
like zooming way in I'm getting to
what's important if I scrolling through
Facebook and I see posts from someone
that lives in Australia my friend from
Australia and it is a local concern
that's actually not I mean I don't
really need to see that yeah what I was
wasn't a newsfeed that would be I
wouldn't want to see them newsfeed of
like parties and stuff that would not
help that would that would be what I
currently have and it's in no way
helpful to my brain I want a calendar
that can be filled with with activities
that I want to participate in and then
when if and when I wanted to start a
soccer team which will never happen so I
want to start some LARPing thing then I
might put that out there but and if I
might say it only goes to my circle of
friends because I don't want to do it
with strangers or I can say you know
what I'm down with strangers and it can
invite people that have that common
interest it's just like time place
people right to be able to have a soccer
team you need a field you need a team
and you need to be able to schedule that
well it could help me with a variety
could find soccer team it could find
soccer field it can find people who want
to have a kickball league Wednesday at 5
p.m. one-off or every Wednesday right
like it can actually help you facilitate
the things that are hard about it and
end the whole and not just a soccer game
which is easy enough to deal with
but everything and I don't want to like
sell this is the idea but like just like
a piece of making life better for the
for the individual user doesn't need to
tackle all areas if it gives you
something truly amazing in your life
which I think orchestrating you know in
my social life and I don't really have a
social life and I'm down with that
even that it's like okay well like I
want to know that if I go to a something
there's gonna be five people that are
not five hundred long before covet
nineteen like I want to know I want it
to be orchestrated for me but that
doesn't mean I want everyone to live my
life I want everyone to have it
orchestrated for them how can I best
help you live your best life whether
that is us focusing on our diets our
food or whether that's focusing on our
social lives whatever it is picking one
aspect and saying what would make your
life better how can we create the tool
to support that and then I think you'd
have a thing with ten thousand people on
it that you just keep adding into it
saying okay now that we know how to get
soccer teams made well guess what we
also can get any literally any group of
people to tackle a problem also together
right let's tackle climate change every
when Monday at 2:00
the speed to analyze background so I
don't think it's me if so I'm play in
the background Daniel and you also have
any ideas for what we could do with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars on social media it's a hard one
to tackle because it is so huge and it's
like do we pick me sure broad and it can
be both its we're not doing it we're
just talking about it well like one one
thing like I'm sorry I don't know how to
pronounce your name but wealth shared in
the comments about the Facebook plug-in
for browser plug-in and I've used
another one similar that different
feature set by the same sort of thing
for manipulates kind of what you see
this the that plug-in takes off a lot of
the numbers and stuff which some people
believe has a negative effect on you so
yeah the other option would be to and
get a group of people together and talk
about what features they want to
surreptitiously change in the you know
and the user interfaces of these systems
and then automate that as a way of
turning on and off certain features
there's a limit to it but it's
definitely doable I've created a few
small ones just for myself actually yeah
so it's another option
I love those ideas that I also think
that it's it's the opposite side from
what I want to tackle everything with
but finding tools that work for
individuals where you don't need the
threshold of people then it doesn't
matter as long as it doesn't cost
thousands of dollars to keep it in
business then you know I mean anyone
else using it is taken away from
Facebook but you create tools that are
like Facebook's not getting your data
even if you're on it Facebook isn't
getting like then that would be huge and
then we solved the problem on the
existing platforms I just don't have the
tech skills to think those things up
yeah I mean you do need enough people to
fund the ongoing maintenance something
like that will be very fragile every
time they change the UI or potentially
break you don't necessarily 10,000
people for that but yeah you know it's
like arms race got it right just to kind
of the the Metro cater that I shared
this just one really interesting example
of like this these numbers are there
because they work and like this posted
two minutes ago you may gives us this
feeling of urgency and it's like oh I
need to engage with this and keeps us
really engaged and so that's why these
numbers are there and that's why when I
first like its darkest and turn it on
and I saw what like how different the
experience is when it just says recently
and and you can realize how many numbers
there have been before that you didn't
even notice and so that's kind of one
example of what what I meant before with
yeah just giving people control over the
interface and giving people control to
turn these kind of designs on and off
and so you like it would be no problem
for Facebook to design it in a way so
that you can choose if you want to have
the infinite feet or if you want to have
let's say ten posts and then you have to
click a button or if you want to see
these metrics or not and so
from a design and tech perspective
that's that's really doable and I think
once we do that then it would have this
dynamic of people realizing all there
are these numbers and they really make
me feel different and when they are
turned off and maybe I feel less anxious
and yeah that that could
just kind of reminds me that there a lot
of this stuff is experiments from some
of the stuff that I've heard and read
about which is inside of something
called game B and they talk a lot about
how things are kind of it's called a
generator function with or something
like a evolutionary thing that you set
in motion and but you kind of you set
the open niches and you can leave open
harmful niches for things to manifest
and the more that you know you think
ahead and guard for possible things that
could happen but you're reducing the
chances for harmful things to come out
of these so yeah I wonder what the
thought experiment is to say well we put
that those numbers when someone posted
something or we don't put it and you
found a way to turn that off
that's a hard thought experiment to run
like way down the road what is this
gonna how's this going to make people
feel but it reminds me that like yeah
how come there isn't a setting right in
facebook that lets me turn that on and
off for myself
and said someone had to come out from
the other side but yeah once we set
these things in motion whatever
experiment you want to run like it's
going to do that within the parameters
that you left open so we're down to the
last few minutes at the very end I like
to go around and say what you think you
can add any closing comments as well but
what do you think is the most powerful
thing we could do with 10,000 people and
$100,000 that you would want to
participate in or you would want to see
in existence try to keep it somewhat
succinct because we only have with you a
few minutes left I like the idea of you
having just listened to the last Daniel
and Bentley I like the idea of creating
a like a menu of plugins right so you
can modify your experience of Facebook
or whatever other platform and with a
pool
10,000 people and $100,000 I think you
could probably create a decent-sized
menu of plugins of various different
kinds of plugins that did various
differently I made various different
alterations to your experience of the
platform and and and just have those
available for people to you I I liked
that I didn't know I didn't know it was
I didn't know it was doable that you
could just download a plug-in and modify
the modify the front-end I think they
could do that it's cool yeah it'll work
in your browser it won't work in the
mobile apps and there's a couple of
other challenges but it might help yeah
so I would like to see a community of
people sharing what changes they would
want to social media and then funding
projects to experiment with that through
you know collective action and whether
that be the plugins or a brand-new start
from scratch or this kind of social
media reader thing that I suggested and
and Falls of mine with what other people
said yeah
about you welcome Daniel I've been even
decided what Eric said I think is pretty
powerful getting a list of the plugins
that exist and then seen the holes and
what plugins don't exist that we could
create together but personally in my
life what I want is something that
drastically impacts my life either helps
me eat better helps me connect more with
people in a way that works for my my
executive dysfunction like I want
something that makes life better right
away they can be that isn't being done
right now that isn't odd like you don't
need to be in game B and wanting to save
the world to be part of this you can see
how it impacts your life and gives you
gives you a benefit and I think there's
something in that space but it's the
most powerful thing I can we can do is
is I think what Eric suggested yeah I
think I mean I have no idea how to do
that with 10,000 people in thousand
hours but I think just having something
that supports me in living by my values
and that makes it really easy and
attractive to my values and that makes
it possible to practice them together I
think that would be really important
because it would kind of change the
social dynamics such that we see each
other's values and we see what we care
about and we can support each other in
choosing in alignment with that and
living in a land with that
I find $100,000 and I already have my
thing built and running and I be
inviting people to try it out the most
practical thing I liked what Bentley
said at first that you could create an
ecosystem of people who want to continue
to work on this problem and people with
the talent to create little experiments
people with the talent who could make
what do you call it just little practice
versions of things to try that could
probably be done community of social
media problem solver experimenters they
carry on to participating next week
we're back for the live solution raising
with the topic of prisons because I was
told that we can't tackle that with
social solution raising that can only be
tackled at the government level so
challenge accepted what can we come up
I've got zero in there like I really
feel like I don't know how we could
affect prisons with ten thousand people
under $1,000 but I look forward to the
discussion so say goodbye to YouTube and
we'll see you next week